<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<cookbook version="47">
<recipe>
<title>Baked Beans</title>
<preptime>30</preptime>
<cooktime>60</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>   2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>   1 onion, diced small</li>
<li>   2 packages (24 ounces) burger crumbles (I use Yves, since MorningStar Farms is no longer vegan)</li>
<li>   2 large cans (28 ounces each) vegetarian baked beans (I prefer Bush's)</li>
<li>   1 large can (6ounces) French fried onions</li>
<li>   1/4 cup ketchup</li>
<li>   1/2 cup BBQ sauce (I prefer Kraft original)</li>
<li>   2 tablespoons yellow mustard</li>
<li>   1/2 cup brown sugar</li>
<li>   nonstick spray    </li>
<li></li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Preheat oven to 350 degrees F. Saute onion in olive oil until soft. Stir in burger crumbles and cook for a couple minutes.  </li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Pour beans into a large bowl. Add onion/crumble mixture and all other ingredients. Spray a 9x13 baking dish with cooking spray and pour beans in.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Top with french fried onions. Cover dish with tin foil and bake for 1 hour.  Remove the foil for the last 15 or 20 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Source of recipe: This is an adaptation of my mom's (meat) baked beans.  It is super easy to make and super yummy!!</li>
<li></li>
<li>Makes: A 9x13 baking dish full, Preparation time: 10 minutes, Cooking time: 1 hour</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=34605.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>5</quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Black Bean Burger </title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 (20 ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained</li>
<li>1/4 cup yellow onion, diced</li>
<li>1/4 cup red bell pepper, diced</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon ground cayenne pepper</li>
<li>1 egg replacer</li>
<li>1 cup seasoned bread crumbs</li>
<li>2 tablespoons fresh chopped cilantro</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Preheat oven to 350 degrees F. Grease baking pan. In a large bowl, mash black beans then add onion, bell pepper, cayenne pepper, egg replacer, vegan bread crumbs and cilantro.</li>
<li>2. Blend until all ingredients are mixed well. Form bean mixture into patties and place on prepared pan.</li>
<li>3. Bake for 10 minutes. Alternatively, fry them in olive oil. I recommend baking them. Serve with garnishes, if desired.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/print/node/35911</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Breakfast Scramble</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    Cheez sauce:</li>
<li>    1/2 cup flour</li>
<li>    1/2 cup nutritional yeast</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon garlic powder</li>
<li>    2 cups water</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon yellow mustard</li>
<li>    4 tablespoons vegan margarine (I use Earth Balance)</li>
<li></li>
<li>    Stir fry:</li>
<li>    1/2 onion, chopped</li>
<li>    1/2 green pepper, chopped</li>
<li>    cooking oil, as needed</li>
<li>    1 pound extra firm tofu, drained and crumbled (not silken style)</li>
<li>    pinch turmeric, optional</li>
<li>    salt and pepper, to taste</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. For cheez sauce, mix first 3 ingredients together in sauce pan. Add water and mix thoroughly. Heat on medium until thick and bubbly. Remove from heat and add mustard and margarine. Set aside.  </li>
<li></li>
<li>2. For stir fry, saute onion and green pepper in oil.  When they are good and soft, move them to the sides of the pan and form an empty circle in the middle for your tofu. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Add more oil to the middle of the pan, then add your drained, crumbled tofu. When it starts to get golden, mix in the peppers and onion and keep frying.  You can add some turmeric for color, if you like. </li>
<li></li>
<li>4. When it looks like you could eat it, add the cheez sauce and mix it all in to coat, until that becomes golden brown too. I saute this for another couple of minutes.  You might not need all of the sauce. I save the leftovers for pizza or nachos. Add salt and pepper to taste (this makes all the difference!).</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=14074.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Brown Rice Black Bean Salad</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 cup cooked brown rice</li>
<li>    1/2 cup rinsed black beans</li>
<li>    1 medium tomato, chopped</li>
<li>    1/2 avocado, chopped</li>
<li>    3 green onions, chopped</li>
<li>    1/4 cup cilantro, chopped, plus whole leaves for garnish</li>
<li>    3 tablespoons cooked corn</li>
<li>    3 tablespoons chopped green chilies</li>
<li>    splash lime juice</li>
<li>    salt, to taste</li>
<li>    pepper, to taste</li>
<li>    3 large red leaf lettuce leaves, chopped</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Except for lettuce leaves, mix all ingredients (rice, black beans, tomato, avocado, onions, cilantro, corn, chilies, lime juice, salt, and pepper).</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Arrange lettuce on a place and top with rice mixture.  </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Garnish with whole cilantro leaves on top and a lime wedge on the side.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=9435.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Carrot Spaghetti </title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3 medium carrots</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>3 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>freshly ground pepper, to taste</li>
<li>1/4 onion, diced, optional</li>
<li>2 small cloves garlic, finely diced</li>
<li>1/4 cup pasta sauce</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Wash the carrots well, especially if they are not organic. With a vegetable peeler, peel the carrots into long thing strips and sprinkle with salt.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Coat the bottom of a large pan with the olive oil and heat on medium-high heat. When hot, add the carrots. Toss frequently (this works well with tongs). When the carrots start to soften, add the garlic and pepper (add onion here too if you like).</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Keep tossing for a couple of minutes until some of the carrots get brown around the edges (don't burn!) and the garlic is golden. Serve with your favorite pasta sauce (tomato based, I really can't vouch for alfredo or other fancy sauces).</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/print/node/40624</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Cashew Fried Rice</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 pound soft tofu, mashed</li>
<li>    1/8 teaspoon turmeric</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon onion powder</li>
<li>    3 tablespoons vegetable oil</li>
<li>    5 cups cold cooked rice</li>
<li>    1/2 cup chopped cashews</li>
<li>    3 small yellow onions, chopped</li>
<li>    sauce:</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon salt ( i usually leave this out)</li>
<li>    3 tablespoons tamari</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon sugar (i use sucanat)</li>
<li>    bok choy</li>
<li>    snap peas</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext>Mix tofu, turmeric, and onion powder in a bowl. Heat 1 tablespoon of the oil in a skillet.  Add the tofu mixture and cook, stirring constantly, about 10 minutes. Remove from heat.  place a dry wok over medium heat. When it begins to smoke, add the remaining oil, the onions, and the rice. Stir fry for 3 minutes. Pour in the sauce (tamari, salt, and vegan sugar) and stir fry until the rice is heated through, about 5 minutes. Stir in the cashews and the scrambled tofu mixture. Enjoy! This is delicious!!</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=9007.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Chickpea Salad Sandwich</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    2 slices whole wheat bread</li>
<li>    chickpeas</li>
<li>    mustard</li>
<li>    soy mayonnaise</li>
<li>    pickle relish</li>
<li>    vegan soy cheese, optional</li>
<li>    lettuce, optional- i like the spring greens mix</li>
<li>    tomato slices, optional</li>
<li>    fresh ground pepper</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext></recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=9649.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Deli Slices</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    2 cups vital wheat gluten</li>
<li>    1 cup vegetarian chicken broth   </li>
<li>    1/4 cup soy sauce</li>
<li>    2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>    2 tablespoons agave nectar</li>
<li>    1/4 teaspoon mesquite liquid smoke</li>
<li>    1/2 cup nutritional yeast flakes   </li>
<li>    1/2 (14 ounce) package firm tofu </li>
<li>    2 teaspoons onion powder</li>
<li>    2 teaspoons poultry seasoning</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon paprika</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon garlic powder</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon black pepper</li>
<li>    1/4 teaspoon turmeric</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. In a large bowl, add the vital wheat gluten. In a food processor, process all the wet ingredients, nutritional yeast, tofu, and spices until smooth.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Pour the wet ingredients into the bowl with the wheat gluten. Mix well with a spoon then knead with hands. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Roll into a log that is 2 1/2-3&quot; wide. Loosely roll foil around the seitan log and twist both ends like a tootsie roll.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Place in a pot with several inches water. Have something holding it from the bottom so it is not touching the water (like a deep cookie cutter).</li>
<li></li>
<li>5. Steam for 1 hour. When done steaming, take out of pot, allow to cool. When cool, slice thinly like deli meat.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=41999.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Ethiopian Cabbage</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 onion, chopped </li>
<li>    5 carrots, cut in chunks</li>
<li>    1/4 cup olive oil</li>
<li>    1/2 large head cabbage, cut into 1&quot; pieces</li>
<li>    2 potatoes, chopped into 1&quot; cubes</li>
<li>    1 cup water</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>    1/2-1 teaspoon cumin</li>
<li>    1/2-1 teaspoon turmeric</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. I used a pressure cooker, but it can be made on the stove with a dutch oven, too. Saute onion and carrot in the oil for 10 minutes. </li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Add the other ingredients and cover. Stir occasionally. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. When all veggies are soft, it is done. Delicious and nutritious.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=31892.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Garlic &amp; Dill Mashed Potatoes</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    8 large red potatoes, peeled and chopped</li>
<li>    4 tablespoons vegan margarine</li>
<li>    1/2 cup plain nondairy milk (I use soy)</li>
<li>    1/4 cup strong not-chicken-broth (I use 1/4 cup hot potato water + 1 teaspoon Better Than Bouillon Not Chicken Base)</li>
<li>    1/4 teaspoon garlic powder</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon dill weed</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon sea salt </li>
<li>    freshly ground black pepper, to taste</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Fill a large, deep soup/stock pot halfway up with water, and add potatoes to the pot. Bring to a boil over high heat until tender, about 10 minutes, give or take.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. While the potatoes are boiling, place the margarine in a large mixing bowl. When the potatoes are done, drain them, reserving 1/4 cup of the boiling water to mix with the bouillon. Place the potatoes on top of the margarine in the bowl and mash with a potato masher. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Blend with an electric hand mixer, slowly adding the milk and broth as you mix. Stop and scrape down the bowl. </li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Add the spices and salt and pepper and mix on high for 1-2 minutes, until nice and fluffy. </li>
<li></li>
<li>If they need to be warmed up, just make sure your bowl is oven-safe and pop them in a 350 degree F oven for a few minutes.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=27549.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>General Tao's Tofu</title>
<preptime>45</preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 (12 ounce) box firm tofu, in 1&quot; cubes (frozen and thawed, if desired)</li>
<li>    1 egg equivalent</li>
<li> (e.g., EnerG Egg Replacer), prepared</li>
<li>    3 tablespoons + 2 tablespoons water, divided</li>
<li>    3/4 cup + 1 tablespoon cornstarch, divided</li>
<li>    vegetable oil for frying + 3 tablespoons vegetable oil, divided</li>
<li>    3 green onions, chopped</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon minced ginger</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon minced garlic</li>
<li>    2/3 cup vegetable stock</li>
<li>    1/4 cup granulated sugar</li>
<li>    2 tablespoons soy sauce</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon white vinegar</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon sherry, optional</li>
<li>    red pepper, to taste</li>
<li>    steamed broccoli, to serve</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Mix the egg replacer as specified on the box and add an additional 3 tablespoons water.  Dip tofu in egg replacer mixture and coat completely.  Sprinkle 3/4 cup cornstarch over tofu and coat completely.  Watch out that the cornstarch doesn't clump up at the bottom of the bowl.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Heat oil in pan and fry tofu pieces until golden. Drain oil. Heat 3 tablespoons vegetable oil in pan on medium heat.  Add green onions, ginger, and garlic; cook for about 2 minutes.  Be careful not to burn garlic.  </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Add vegetable stock, sugar, soy sauce, vinegar, sherry, and red pepper.  </li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Mix 2 tablespoons water with 1 tablespoon cornstarch and pour into mixture stirring well.  Add fried tofu and coat evenly.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serve immediately with steamed broccoli over your choice of rice.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=8769.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>4</quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Ginger Soba Noodles</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient>This URL is not compatible with My CookBook</ingredient>
<recipetext></recipetext>
<url>http://www.101cookbooks.com/archives/ginger-soba-noodles-recipe.html</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Green Bean Cassarole</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1-1/2 cups nondairy milk</li>
<li>    1 (2.5-ounce) cube veggie bouillon</li>
<li>    1 to 2 tablespoons vegetable oil</li>
<li>    1/2 medium onion, diced</li>
<li>    3/4 cup chopped mushrooms (button, crimini, portabella, whatever)</li>
<li>    1 carrot, diced</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon basil</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon garlic</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon marjoram</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon oregano</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon pepper</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon sage</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon thyme</li>
<li>    2 or 3 tablespoons cornstarch or potato starch</li>
<li>    2 or 3 tablespoons cold water</li>
<li>    1 (14.5-ounce) can French cut green beans</li>
<li>    1-1/2 (24-ounce) canisters vegan French fried onions</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. In a saucepan, heat the nondairy milk and veggie bouillon; stir until bouillon cube disintegrates. Just heat the milk, do not boil or scald it.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. In a skillet, heat the oil. Add the onions, mushrooms, and carrots; saute until the onions are translucent. Add the herbs and spices (basil, garlic, marjoram, oregano, pepper, sage, salt, and thyme - and whatever other hearty herbs make you happy).</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Make a thickener by combining cornstarch and cold water; mix well. Pour into the nondairy milk-bouillon mixture. Stir well, because this will coagulate pretty quickly. </li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Quickly add the can of green beans, the sautéed veggies, and about half of the French fried onions; stir well. Pour that mixture into a casserole dish or pan and top with remaining French fried onions. </li>
<li></li>
<li>5. Bake at 350 degrees Fahrenheit for 10 to 15 minutes, or until the French fried onions begin to brown.  Remove. Eat. Enjoy.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=6137.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Lemon Dill Potato Salad</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    6 or 7 medium potatoes (any variety), peeled and diced to 1” cubes (about 4-5 cups)</li>
<li>    ½ teaspoon onion powder</li>
<li>    ½ teaspoon garlic powder</li>
<li>    ½ teaspoon dried dill or 1 teaspoon fresh chopped dill</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon salt (to salt the water in the pot)</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon salt (to salt the water in the pot)</li>
<li>    ½ cup vegan mayonnaise (I use Vegenaise)</li>
<li>    2 teaspoons Dijon mustard</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon lemon juice</li>
<li>    2 large or 3 small celery stalks, chopped</li>
<li>    2 tablespoons finely chopped onion</li>
<li>    2 tablespoons chopped chives</li>
<li>    ¾ teaspoon dried dill or 1 ½ teaspoon fresh chopped dill</li>
<li>    ¼ teaspoon paprika</li>
<li>    ½ to 1 teaspoon salt (to taste)</li>
<li>    ½ teaspoon pepper</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Add potatoes, 1 tablespoon salt, ½ teaspoon dried dill or 1 teaspoon fresh dill, onion powder, and garlic powder to pot and fill pot with cool tap water until just above the surface of the potatoes. Bring to a simmer over medium heat and simmer another 5-10 minutes, until fork tender. Do not overcook.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. While potatoes are cooking, get a bowl big enough for the salad. Add the rest of the ingredients to the bowl and stir to make the dressing. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Drain potatoes and add them to the dressing while they’re still warm. Gently toss to coat and leave uncovered for about 30-40 minutes, until they come to room temperature. Then cover and refrigerate for at least two hours.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=33149.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Lentil Carrot Burger</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 cup uncooked lentils</li>
<li>3 carrots, grated</li>
<li>1 onion, diced</li>
<li>3/4 cup whole grain flour, as needed</li>
<li>pinch sea salt and black pepper</li>
<li>1 teaspoon coriander</li>
<li>1 teaspoon cumin</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper</li>
<li>1 to 2 teaspoon(s) olive oil</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Before you begin, the lentils must be fully cooked. Gently boil them in enough water to cover them by 2 &quot;, with NO salt. Lentils will take about 30 minutes to cook. Drain lentils and place in bowl.</li>
<li>2. Add carrots and onion. Mash them a bit, but not too much. Add enough flour to get them to the point where they will stick together. You may also need to add a bit of water.</li>
<li>3. Season the mix with the spices (coriander, cumin, cayenne pepper, salt, and black pepper); stir them through well. With your hands, form the lentil mix into burger shapes.</li>
<li>4. Add a teaspoon of olive oil to a heated pan and lay the burgers in. Leave them for about 10 minutes on the first side, flip, and cook another 5 to 7 minutes. Put the burgers in an oven on low heat to keep them warm while you cook the second batch.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/print/node/45588</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Lentil Sloppy Joes </title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 cup lentils</li>
<li>    2 cups water</li>
<li>    2 tablespoons minced onion</li>
<li>    2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon sugar</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon dry mustard</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon chili powder</li>
<li>    2 teaspoons green pepper flakes </li>
<li>    (If you can not find green pepper flakes, add fresh green pepper sauteed until soft)</li>
<li>    2 teaspoons cornstarch</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon dry minced garlic (the kind in the spice section)</li>
<li>    1/2 teaspoon celery seeds</li>
<li>    1 (6 ounce) can tomato paste</li>
<li>    1 1/4 cups water</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Rinse and pick through lentils.  Add two cups water to pan with lentils and bring to boil.  Cover, reduce heat, and simmer about 55 minutes until tender, but not mushy.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. For the sauce, combine the minced onion, salt, sugar, dry mustard, chili powder, green pepper flakes, cornstarch, minced garlic, and celery seeds. Combine well and set aside. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. When lentils are done, add the tomato paste and water.  Stir in the sauce seasoning.  Combine well and heat through. </li>
<li></li>
<li>Serve on whole wheat buns or over brown rice. Makes excellent left overs too!!!</li>
<li></li>
<li>Note: The dry ingredients can be combined and stored in snack size baggies for your own homemade sloppy joe seasoning to use anytime.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=29868.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Lentil Soup with Sweet Potato</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 lb lentils</li>
<li>    1 lb sweet potatoes, peeled and diced</li>
<li>    1 cup diced onion (Vidalia if available)</li>
<li>    3-4 stalks celery - sliced</li>
<li>    32 oz vegetable broth</li>
<li>    3 - 4 cups water</li>
<li>    (optional - other soup vegetables)</li>
<li>    1 tbs+ oil (I use Canola)</li>
<li>    organic raw sugar (to taste - 1-3 tbs.)</li>
<li>    2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>    basil to taste</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Sauté onions in oil until soft. Add all other ingredients and bring to a boil.  Simmer until tender (about an hour).  This soup tastes best if left to sit on the stove a couple of hours before serving.</li>
<li></li>
<li>The vegetables tend to disappear in this soup so if you prefer them more firm, add them 1/2 hour after the lentils.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=10255.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Mesir W'et</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 cup dried red lentils</li>
<li>    1 onion, chopped</li>
<li>    1-3 cloves garlic, minced</li>
<li>    oil, for frying</li>
<li>    2 cups vegetable broth or water</li>
<li>    1 (6 ounce) can tomato paste</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon paprika</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon ground ginger</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon turmeric</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon Garam Masala</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon berbere or an additional 1 tablespoon paprika or 1 tablespoon cayenne pepper</li>
<li>    sea salt and pepper, to taste</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Soak lentils for at least an hour in water. Drain and rinse and set aside. Saute onions and garlic in oil until golden. </li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Add broth or water. Add spices and tomato paste. When gently boiling, add lentils. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Turn down heat and simmer until lentils are tender and it's a thick stew, adding more liquid if needed. Serve with rice, Injera bread or pita bread. </li>
<li></li>
<li>This is a recipe that I've tweaked to perfection and everyone asks me to bring to any potluck or party. If you can find a market that sells berere (a spice blend) it will taste more authentic. You can find recipes for the spice blend online or see the recipe for substitutes if you are in a hurry. This is usually served with injera, a flat pancake like bread. If you can't find that you could serve this with rice or pita bread.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=22067.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Mexican Brown Rice</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 cup onion, diced</li>
<li>    1 bell pepper, diced</li>
<li>    2 cloves garlic, chopped</li>
<li>    1 1/2 cups brown rice</li>
<li>    oil, as needed</li>
<li>    3 cups vegetable stock (I use cubes)</li>
<li>    1 (15 ounce) can diced tomatoes, undrained</li>
<li>    1 tablespoon chili powder</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon oregano</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon cumin</li>
<li>    cayenne, to taste</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Stir fry the onion, pepper, garlic and rice in oil until onions are transparent. </li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Add the stock and tomatoes plus the juice. Bring to a boil, and stir in herbs.  </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Reduce heat, cover and simmer for 40 minutes, or until rice is done and liquid gone. Fluff and serve. Should be a tad sticky.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=14047.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Mushroom Burger </title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 cups water</li>
<li>1/4 cup Braggs Liquid Aminos or soy sauce</li>
<li>1 tablespoon vegetable stock base (I used Vogue brand)</li>
<li>2 tablespoon nutritional yeast</li>
<li>2 tablespoon powdered egg replacer, no added water (I use Ener-G Egg Replacer)</li>
<li>1 8 oz package tempeh, crumbled</li>
<li>12-16 oz mushrooms (any, but I prefer crimini)</li>
<li>1 cup walnuts</li>
<li>1/2 re onion</li>
<li>3/4 cup carrots</li>
<li>1/2 cup or more, whole wheat flour</li>
<li>3 cups regular oats (not the quick cook kind)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Place water, braggs, nutritional yeast, egg replacer, stock base and crumbled tempeh in a large pot and bring to a boil. In a food processor, grind the walnuts, mushrooms, onions and carrots and add to the pot. Boil this mixture for 5 minutes. In a second bowl, combine the oats, and flour, add to the pot. cook on medium for 5-8 minutes, or until extremely thick. pour into a bowl and chill for 2 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Preheat oven to 350 degrees F. Scoop out oat mixture and shape into patties of desired thickness, I usually get about 14 from this recipe. Place on a lightly sprayed baking sheet and cook for 15-25 minutes per side.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cool, wrap and freeze until ready to use.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/print/node/41001</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Mushroom Risotto</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 cup brown basmati rice </li>
<li>    salt and pepper, to taste </li>
<li>    1/4 cup white wine, optional</li>
<li>    1 teaspoon olive oil </li>
<li>    1 cup mushrooms, sliced </li>
<li>    1 lemon, zested and juiced    </li>
<li>    1 handful fresh parsley, chopped    </li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Heat 3 cups water in a small pot to just below a boil. Warm another pot to medium, add the rice and a pinch sea salt, and stir it while allowing it to brown slightly. Pour the wine over the rice, and stir until it is all absorbed by the rice. Use water if you prefer. </li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Next, add the heated water to the rice, about 1/2 cup at a time, stirring constantly and waiting for all the liquid to be absorbed before adding more. </li>
<li></li>
<li>3. While this is cooking, heat a small pan to medium-high and saute the mushrooms in olive oil. Once they are fully cooked, add the lemon zest and juice. </li>
<li></li>
<li>4. You can marinate the mushrooms rather than saute if you wish, by putting them in a container with a lid, sprinkling them with salt and lemon juice, and shaking them. Allow them to sit, shaking occasionally, for about an hour to soften.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5. Use all 3 cups water for a very liquid, creamy risotto, or add only 2-2 1/2 cups for a sticky risotto. Once all the liquid is absorbed, test the rice to see if it is done. It should be soft, but only just cooked (al dente). Stir in the mushrooms and parsley, season with black pepper, and serve. </li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=40983.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Naan</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 (1/4 ounce) package active dry yeast</li>
<li>1 cup warm water</li>
<li>1/4 cup sugar</li>
<li>3 tablespoons nondairy milk (I use soy)</li>
<li>1 egg replacer, beaten (1 1/2 teaspoons powder, 2 tablespoons warm water)</li>
<li>2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>4 1/2 cups bread flour</li>
<li>1 teaspoon minced garlic</li>
<li>margarine and/or oil, as needed</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. In a large bowl, dissolve yeast in warm water. Let stand about 10 minutes. It will look frothy. Add and stir sugar, milk, egg replacer, and salt.</li>
<li>2. Add enough flour to make a soft dough. I drop in 1/2 cup at a time and stir until doughy. Knead for 1-2 minutes on a lightly floured surface, until smooth. Place dough in a lightly oiled bowl, cover with a damp cloth, and set aside to rise. Let it rise for at least 1 hour.</li>
<li>3. Push down dough, and knead in garlic slowly. Make sure garlic is spread throughout and not concentrated into one area. Pinch off small handfuls of dough and roll into 2&quot; diameter balls. Place on a cookie sheet or other tray. Cover with a towel, and allow to rise for 30 minutes.</li>
<li>4. Heat a griddle on the stove top at medium heat. Make sure to lightly oil griddle with cooking spray between each naan. Roll one ball of dough out into a thin elongated circle/oval with rolling pin. Place dough on grill, and cook for 2 to 3 minutes, or until puffy and lightly browned.</li>
<li>5. Flip and cook another 2 to 4 minutes. The air bubbles that form in the dough while cooking should be the dark browned parts of the naan. Don't press bread down to cook through. Remove from grill, and continue the process until all the naan has been prepared.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/print/node/44195</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Pad Thai</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 pound rice noodles (wide ones)</li>
<li>    1 pound extra firm tofu, pressed</li>
<li>    canola oil, as needed</li>
<li>    1/2 cup soy sauce</li>
<li>    3/4 cup white vinegar</li>
<li>    3/4 cup sugar</li>
<li>    3 teaspoons sambal olek chili paste </li>
<li>    (or 2 tablespoons ketchup + 2 teaspoons paprika)</li>
<li>    2 teaspoons finely chopped garlic</li>
<li>    8 green onions, chopped into 1&quot; pieces</li>
<li>    4 cups bean sprouts</li>
<li>    3/4 cup roasted peanuts, roughly chopped</li>
<li>    lime wedges, to serve</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Cover the noodles with warm water in a large bowl and allow them to soak for 30 minutes. They should be flexible and soft, but not soft enough to be mashed with your fingers. Drain them and put them aside. </li>
<li></li>
<li>2. For tofu, you can thinly slice into bite sized pieces and bake on a lightly oiled pan at 375 degrees Fahrenheit for 15 minutes on each side, or cube the tofu and fry in about 1/2 cup oil in a very hot wok. Fry the tofu until lightly browned. Remove from the oil and drain.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Mix the soy sauce, vinegar, sugar, and sambal olek in a bowl. Stir until well blended. The sugar won't dissolve completely, but that's okay. Heat several tablespoons oil in a medium hot wok and add the noodles coating them with the oil. </li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Add the soy sauce mixture and garlic into the wok and bring to a boil while gently folding the noodles. Lower the heat a bit and keep the liquid boiling while frequently folding the noodles. Try not to break the noodles. </li>
<li></li>
<li>5. When almost all the liquid has been absorbed, add the tofu and green onions and cook for about 2 minutes longer, until the tofu is warm and the onions are bright green. Serve the Pad Thai with a heavy garnish of bean sprouts and peanuts with lime wedges on the side.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=14784.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Red pepper and potato soup </title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil, plus a drizzle for serving</li>
<li>1 medium onion, chopped</li>
<li>1 large carrot, peeled and chopped</li>
<li>Salt, preferably kosher</li>
<li>4 plump garlic cloves, green shoots removed, minced</li>
<li>1 tablespoon tomato paste</li>
<li>2 pounds (4 large) red bell peppers, seeded, membranes removed, cut in large dice</li>
<li>2 teaspoons sweet paprika</li>
<li>1 pound russet potatoes (about 2 medium), peeled and diced</li>
<li>2 quarts chicken or vegetable stock</li>
<li>A bouquet garni made with a bay leaf and a couple of sprigs each thyme and parsley, tied together in a bundle</li>
<li>Freshly ground pepper</li>
<li>For garnish (optional):</li>
<li>Garlic croutons (toast thin slices of baguette and rub with a cut clove of garlic)</li>
<li>Slivered basil leaves or chopped fresh thyme leaves</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Heat the olive oil over medium heat in a large, heavy soup pot, and add the onion and carrot. Cook, stirring often, until the onion begins to soften, and then add 1/2 teaspoon salt. Continue to cook, stirring often, until tender, about 5 minutes, and stir in the garlic and tomato paste. Stir for a minute or two, until the garlic is fragrant and the tomato paste has darkened, and then add the peppers, paprika, and another 1/2 teaspoon salt. Cook, stirring often, until the peppers begin to soften, about 5 minutes.</li>
<li>2. Add the potatoes, stock, and bouquet garni, and bring to a simmer. Add salt to taste, one to two teaspoons, cover and simmer over low heat for one hour. Remove the bouquet garni.</li>
<li>3. Blend the soup until smooth in an immersion blender, or in a blender or food processor fitted with a steel blade. Work in batches, and cover the blender lid or food processor with a kitchen towel to prevent the hot soup from splashing. Strain the soup through a medium strainer, pushing it through the strainer with a spatula or the bowl of a ladle, and return to the heat. Heat through, add salt and pepper to taste, and serve. Garnish with garlic croutons and slivered fresh basil or chopped thyme, and drizzle a few drops of olive oil over each serving if desired.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.nytimes.com/2008/09/25/health/nutrition/25recipehealth.html?_r=1</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Thai Green Curry Lentils </title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>    1 cup red lentils</li>
<li>    2 cups vegetable broth</li>
<li>    olive oil, as needed</li>
<li>    salt and pepper, to taste</li>
<li>    1 medium onion, finely chopped</li>
<li>    2 cloves garlic, finely chopped</li>
<li>    1 red, orange or yellow bell pepper, finely chopped</li>
<li>    1 large zucchini, chopped into bite sized pieces</li>
<li>    1 (14 ounce) can light coconut milk </li>
<li>    1 tablespoon green curry paste </li>
<li>    1 small (thumbnail sized) piece fresh ginger, peeled and finely grated </li>
<li>    1 bunch Swiss chard, stems removed, finely chopped</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. In a stock pot, combine vegetable broth and lentils with a splash of olive oil and a pinch of salt and pepper. Bring to a boil, reduce heat, cover and simmer until liquid is absorbed, about 15 minutes. Check the lentils frequently so they don't burn.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. While the lentils cook, add olive oil to a large skillet with deep sides and saute onions and garlic until just translucent. Add bell pepper and saute until soft. Add zucchini and saute for 1 minute.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. At this point, the lentils should be finished cooking. Add coconut milk, green curry paste, grated ginger, and lentils to the skillet, stirring gently to incorporate vegetables and liquid. Bring mixture to a boil, reduce heat, cover and simmer for 2 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Add Swiss chard to liquid and simmer 1 minute. Remove from heat, season with salt and pepper to taste. Enjoy!</li>
<li></li>
<li>The finished product should be a thick stew-like consistency; you can eat it with a spoon by itself or serve it over rice!</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://vegweb.com/index.php?topic=29449.0</url>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<comments></comments>
</recipe>

</cookbook>
